Guide to the Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records, 1968-2002 AIS.1979.21
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records
1968-2002
ULS Archives & Special Collections
GASP (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1979.21
10.89 Linear Feet (13 boxes, 1 oversize file)
The Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records (1968-2002) comprises a wide variety of material documenting the activities of this environmental organization. Areas of concentration include administrative records, legal cases, outreach efforts and environmental issues, such as acid rain, energy, transportation, hazardous waste and water. Additionally, legal records documenting court cases involving the companies United States Steel, Ling-Temco-Vought (LTV) and Shenango, Inc. are included as well as litigation materials of air pollution cases, state implementation plans and other environmental legal cases.
History
The Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) was founded as a non-profit citizens' group in 1969 by a group of 43 volunteers in southwestern Pennsylvania working for a "healthy, sustainable environment." Over the years, the group has worked to improve environmental standards in the region through educational programs and a quarterly newsletter, Hotline. In the 1970s, GASP entered into litigation in Federal District Court to require Allegheny County to adopt standards based on the Clean Air Act of 1970. In the 1980s, GASP cooperated with the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) in bringing about enforcement of air quality standards at the US Steel Coke production facilities at its Clairton Works.
The mission statement of the organization is as follows: "GASP will act to obtain for the residents of Western Pennsylvania clean air, water, and land in order to create the healthy, sustainable environment and quality of life to which we are all entitled." As of 2011, the organization is still active and continues to work to educate the public on questions of pollution and its remediation. GASP's website can be found through this link: http://gasp-pgh.org/.
Scope and Content Notes
The Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records contain materials relating to this environmental organization between 1968 and 2002. This collection is comprised of correspondence; diagrams; schematic plans; reports; financial records; by-laws; awards; staff biographies; publications; statements; court documents; newspaper clippings; photographs; membership lists; testimonies; and policies. Areas of concentration include administrative records, legal cases, outreach efforts and environmental issues including acid rain, energy, transportation, hazardous waste and water. Additionally, legal records documenting court cases involving the companies United States Steel, Ling-Temco-Vought (LTV) and Shenango, Inc. are included as well as litigation materials of air pollution cases, state implementation plans and other environmental legal cases.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Accruals
A substantial amount of more material (10 linear feet) was donated to ASC by Gladys Maharam on March 31, 2009. In April 2011, James Longhurst, Assistant Professor of History, University of Wisconsin, La Crosse, returned materials that a former GASP president had loaned to him in order complete his personal research.
Acquisition Information
GASP donated three boxes of material to the ASC on July 31, 1979.
Previous Citation
Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records, 1968-2002, AIS.1979.21, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records, 1971-1976, AIS.1979.21, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
Additional scope notes are found at the series and subseries level. The collection is divided into six series. Series III. Legal has been arranged into six subseries. Series I through Series V are arranged chronologically, while Series VI is arranged alphabetically.
Series I. Administrative, 1969-1994
Series II. Board of Directors, 1969-1999
Series III. Legal, 1969-2002
Series IV. Outreach, 1968-1993
Series V. Subject Files, 1970-1996
Series VI. Related Companies, 1971-1976
Related Material
Jeannette Widom Papers Relating to GASP, 1970-1981, AIS.1994.10, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Smog -- United States; Air -- Pollution -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Societies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Correspondence; Petitions; Environmental protection -- Pennsylvania -- Societies, etc.; Natural resources -- Pennsylvania; Natural resources -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Associations; Pollution -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Environment; Allegheny County (Pa.). Air Pollution Variance Board; GASP (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Administrative, 1969-1994; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series dates between 1969 and 1994 and contains the administrative records of GASP. The documents found in the Administrative series include public relations and financial records, correspondence, by-laws, meeting minutes, awards, staff biographies, pamphlets and statements of the group. The material is arranged chronologically.
  - Public Relations, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Form Letter and Related Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Public Relations Correspondence and Announcements, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters to the Editor Correspondence, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Forms, ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - By-Laws, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1970-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Representative Lists and Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Public Relations Mailing Lists, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Awards and Related Materials, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Staff Biographies and Resumes, 1971-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases and Related Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Film Advertisements and Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Public Relations, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Public Service Announcements, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Public Relations, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Treasurers' Reports, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Public Relations, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Donor Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Dictionary and Glossaries, ca. early 1980s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Membership Advertisements, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Questionnaires, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fiscal Records, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mascot Correspondence and Skit Script, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Announcements of Meetings and Membership Options, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Recycling Statement, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Board of Directors, 1969-1999; II.
  The Board of Directors series includes three categories: Records, Correspondence, and Annual Meeting Records. Within each of these three categories the folders are arranged chronologically. The dates of the series range from 1969 to 1999. This series includes documents produced and received by and the Board of Directors of GASP including meeting minutes and correspondence.
  - Records, 1969-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1-15)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1995 (Box 3, Folder 16-32)
  - Annual Meeting Records, 1970-1992 (Box 3, Folder 33-42)
- Legal, 1969-2002; III.
  The Legal series (1969-2002) is divided into six subseries: United States Steel; State Implementation Plans; Ling-Temco-Vought (LTV); Shenango, Inc.; Air Pollution; and Other. This series includes court documents, correspondence, testimonies, media coverage and reports about the legal cases involving GASP. Within each subseries the folders are arranged chronologically. Further scope notes are available at the subseries level.
  - United States Steel, 1969-1995; 1.
    The United States Steel subseries includes information on several litigations that involved the United States Steel Company (also known as U.S. Steel, U.S.S. and U.S.X.) and GASP. These include the Clairton Coke Works dispute and the Mon Valley Consent Decree Case. The materials in this subseries range from 1969 to 1995 and are arranged chronologically.
    - Clairton Coke Works Correspondence and Court Documents, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Steel Workers Records, 1969-1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings about United States Steel, 1971-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Court Documents, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Media Coverage about Clairton Coke Works, 1971-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Media Coverage and Testimonies about Clairton Coke Works, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Task Force Report and Correspondence about Clairton Coke Works and U.S.S. Steel, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Clairton Task Force Report and Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - News Releases, Testimony and Meeting Notes about the Clairton Coke Works, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Testimony, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Clairton Coke Works Correspondence, Reports and Press Releases, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Clairton Coke Works Observations Film Negatives, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Clairton Coke Works Newspaper Clippings and Statements, 1975-1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Clairton Coke Works Case Court Documents, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence about the Clairton Coke Plant, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Clairton Court Case Documents and Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, Newspaper Clipping and Report about the Steel Industry, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Steel Communities Meeting Materials, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Bubble" Plan Records, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Mon Valley Consent Decrees, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - U.S.S. Steel Corporation Civil Action 79-709 Consent Decree, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - United States Steel Workers of America Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and Reports about the Mon Valley Consent Decrees, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Extension Act Court Documents and Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mon Valley Consent Decree Correspondence and Court Documents, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Civil Action No. 79-709 Court Documents, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Mon Valley Works Road Dust Control Program Consent Decree, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Coke Quench Waters Study Report and Research, 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Clairton Court Case Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Clairton Coke Pollution Citizens Risk Assessment Documentation, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Clairton Coke Plant Statistics, Correspondence and Court Documents, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - United States Versus USX Corporation Second Consent Decree, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - USX Corporation Court Documents, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - USX Settlement Correspondence, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - USX Corporation Court Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - State Implementation Plans, 1979-1995; 2.
    The State Implementation Plans subseries includes materials from the PM10 and the Environmental Protection Agency state implementation plans. Several folders contain records of how the plans affect Allegheny County in particular. The materials (1979-1995) include meeting records, correspondence, testimonies, reports, media coverage and settlement agreements. It is arranged chronologically.
    - Environmental Protection Agency State Implementation Plan Public Meeting Records, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Statements, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Testimony, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Documentation, 1979-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Report on Suspended Particulates, March 24, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hearings Records, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Testimonies, November 12, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny County Testimony and Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - PM10 State Implementation Plan Testimony, News Releases, Correspondence and Reports, 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny County Reports, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Lincoln Borough Power Source Records, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - PM10 Subcommittee Meeting Notes, Correspondence and News Releases, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Liberty Borough/Clairton Area PM10 Area Reports and Correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - PM10 Settlement Agreements, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ling-Temco-Vought (LTV), 1993-2002; 3.
    The Ling-Temco-Vought (LTV) subseries includes records of the lawsuit of LTV vs. the United States Environmental Protection Agency and GASP. The pollution of LTV's Coke Mills is the topic of the legal documents. Correspondence, media coverage, permit applications, lawsuit documents, position statements and interrogatories from the public comprise this subseries. The records (1993-2002) are arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence about LTV Steel and Proposed Coke Plant, 1993-2002 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Media Coverage and Related Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Air Quality Program Permit Application, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Lawsuit Documents, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Position Statements about the LTV Site, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence and Resume of Attorney Robert Yuhnke, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Interrogatories, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Court Documents and Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Motions to Intervene, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Court and Attorney Records, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence and Court Documents, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Shenango, Inc., 1980-2001; 4.
    The Shenango, Inc. subseries includes materials from the legal case relating to the air pollution violations of Shenango, Inc.'s coke-making facilities. Materials include correspondence, court documents, newspaper clippings, advertisements and meeting records. The subseries (1980-2001) is arranged chronologically.
    - Air Pollution Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings and Legal Documents, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Public Comments in Opposition to Proposed Installation Permit for the Coke Making Facilities, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Exhibited Court Documents, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Environmental Protection Agency for Civil Contempt, September 1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Public Hearing Advertisements and Comments, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Meeting Documents, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Background Information about Antaeus Energy-Shenango, Inc., 1999 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence Disputing GASP's Position, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Notice of Intent Document, July 22, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Press Clippings about Shenango, Inc. Violations, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Court Documents, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Air Pollution, 1970-1996; 5.
    The Air Pollution subseries includes materials related to various bills and court cases involving air pollution violations and regulations. A large portion of this subseries includes materials documenting the Clean Air Act as well as the health effects of polluted air. The materials (1970-1996) are arranged chronologically.
    - Health Effects of Air Pollution Testimony, Correspondence and Photograph, 1969-1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Allegheny County Air Pollution Appeals and Variance Review Board Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Testimonies, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Allegheny County Air Code Variance Board Records, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Speeches, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Chamber of Commerce Air Pollution Hearings Testimony, December 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny County Air Pollution Appeals and Variance Review Board Report, December 23, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Control Regulations, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Testimonies, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania State Legislature Air Pollution Meeting Testimony, Correspondence and News Releases, February 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny County Article XVIII Air Pollution Control News Releases, Testimony and Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny County Health Department Article XVIII Rules and Regulations, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Clean Air Act Correspondence and Reports, 1973-1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Clean Air Act Testimony, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Clean Air Act Compliance Regulation Reports and Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Clean Air Act Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Clean Air Act News Releases, Reports and Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Clean Air Act Amendments, 1976-1990 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Environmental Protection Agency Air Pollution Control Policy Statement, November 29, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Air Pollution Control Advisory Board Records, 1979-1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Pennsylvania Environmental Quality Board Statements and Correspondence about Air Pollution, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Testimonies, 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Clean Air Act Press Conference Records, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clean Air Council Newsletters and Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Air Pollution Control Plan Meeting Testimony, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Clean Indoor Act Records, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Clean Air Act Correspondence and News Releases, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Air Toxics Control Act Correspondence and Fact Sheet, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Clean Air Bill Correspondence and News Releases, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Clean Air Alert Materials, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Operating Permit Program for Air Pollution Control Records, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Bureau of Air Quality Control Title V Permit Materials, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence and Press Releases about the Allegheny County Air Quality Control Program, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Testimony about Air Pollution Control Regulations, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Other, 1970-1996; 6.
    The Other subseries includes court cases and environmental legislation materials that do not fit into the other subseries within the Legal series. Included is information about noise control, water policy, various Pennsylvania legislature environmental bills and court cases against specific companies. This subseries (1970-1996) includes correspondence, testimonies, mailing lists, proposals and reports.
    - Correspondence and Lists of Possible Attorneys, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Testimony about the Energy Crisis, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Hearings Mailing Lists, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Environmental Quality Board Testimony, January 17, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Variance Board Petition Records against Pram, Inc., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny County Health Department Testimony, February 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Noise Control Legislation Proposals and Statements, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Senate Bill 1248 Testimony, February 27, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Meeting Report with Congressman Walgren about Environmental Groups, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Environmental Protection Agency Court Documents, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Governor Thornburgh's Private Sector Initiatives Task Force Subcommittee on Impediments Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - House Bill 1236 "Right to Know" Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Arlen Specter, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Environmental Protection Agency Notice of Findings, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Ohio and Appalachian Power Companies Court Case Correspondence, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Environmental Quality Board Reviews and Testimony, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - National Water Policy Records, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - USA Versus Jones and Laughlin Steel, Inc. Court Documents, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Senate Bill 1211 Statements, Correspondence and Testimony, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Packet of Statements Gathered at the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Public Hearing on Proposed Coke Oven Emission Standards, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Pennsylvania Legislature House Bill 1376 Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence and Comments on Senate Bill 1650 and House Bill 2196, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Ohio River Basin Environmental Council Correspondence, News Releases and Newsletters, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Pollution Prevention and Incineration Alternative Act Correspondence, News Release and Report, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Environmental Protection Agency Public Hearing Transcript, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Outreach, 1968-1993; IV.
  The Outreach series includes materials that document the outreach efforts of GASP. Included are materials from environmental task forces, workshops, grants, publications and projects. Correspondence, reports, news releases, financial records, membership lists and photographs comprise this series. It is arranged chronologically from 1968 to 1993.
  - Speaker's Bureau Materials, 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Environmental Protection Agency Correspondence, Reports and Brochures, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence with Pennsylvania Legislatures, 1970-1983 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Testimony Workshops Materials, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Project Environmental Rebirth Grant Records, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Pollution Land Tour Materials, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Leadership Seminar for Citizen Action Information Packet, October 1972 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Earth Week Public Information Seminar Packet, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Monongahela River Enforcement Conference Materials, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare/Environmental Protection Agency Grant Proposals and Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Project Environmental Rebirth Grant Records, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - State Citizens' Advisory Council Records, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Citizens' Advisory Council Reports, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Citizens' Environmental Task Force Records, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Party Cookies Only" Cookbook Correspondence, News Releases and Financial Records, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Citizens" Environmental Task Force Reports, August 1973-July 1974 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Just Coffeecake" Cookbook Correspondence, News Releases and Photograph, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Fun Buns" Cookbook Correspondence, News Releases and Financial Records, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Project Environmental Library Outreach Materials, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Project Pacesetter Records, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Speakers Bureau Meeting Records, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Grant Application for Project Water Shortage Crisis Prevention, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Citizen Air Quality/Transportation Project Grant Proposal, Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Second Environmental Decade White House Celebration Correspondence, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence about the Year of the Coast Program, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvanians United to Rescue the Environment Records, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)